[music]
[音乐]
Hello and welcome to part two
您好，欢迎来到第二部分
of lesson three. In this part we going talk about
第三课在这一部分，我们将讨论
finite and infinite streams and how we deal with those.
有限和无限流以及我们如何处理这些流。
If we look Java
如果我们看Java
and we look at imperative processing,
我们来看命令式处理
we often have situations where we don't know how long
我们经常遇到不知道要多久的情况
a loop needs to run for. So we have to deal with
需要运行一个循环。所以我们必须处理
an indeterminate links for our loop.
我们循环的不确定链接。
we can do that very easily. So we can use something like this,
我们可以很轻松地做到这一点。所以我们可以使用这样的东西
where we have a while loop we simply say while true. So in theory, the loop is
在我们有一个while循环的地方，我们只说while为真。所以从理论上讲，循环是
infinite. Within the loop we do some processing, so
无穷。在循环中，我们进行了一些处理，因此
we're doing something and then we have a test.
我们正在做某事，然后我们进行了测试。
We test to see whether some criteria is true
我们测试一下是否符合某些条件
and, if it is, we can break out of the loop.
如果是这样，我们可以跳出循环。
Until that criteria is true will continue to do this loop,
在该条件为真之前，将继续执行此循环，
so will loop indefinitely until that statement is true
因此将无限期循环直到该语句为真
and then we will break out of it. Now
然后我们将打破它。现在
for a stream remember we don't have explicit loop,
对于流，请记住我们没有显式循环，
so how do we use an infinite stream
那么我们如何使用无限流
and at some point decide that we want to stop using that
并决定我们要停止使用它
stream? There are two things we can use that:
流？我们可以使用两件事：
we can use to findFirst terminal operation,
我们可以使用findFirst终端操作，
or we can use findAny. Remember that the difference between a these
或者我们可以使用findAny。请记住，这些之间的区别
is that findFirst works with,
是findFirst与之合作的，
both sequential and parallel streams, findAny
顺序流和并行流，findAny
is suitable for a parallel stream where you're not worried about
适用于您无需担心的并行流
any particular stream finding the result. So
找到结果的任何特定流。所以
you can findAny, any of the parallel threads
您可以找到任何并行线程中的任何一个
can find a value that's appropriate
可以找到合适的值
and that will terminate the stream. What that means, in effect,
这将终止流。这实际上意味着什么
is that findAny give you non-deterministic results
是findAny给您不确定的结果
if you apply the same set of data repeatedly. If you use findFirst
如果您重复应用同一组数据。如果您使用findFirst
you always get the same result regardless of whether you're using a
无论您是否正在使用
sequential
顺序的
or parallel stream.
或并行流。
In terms of an example, what I've got here is
举个例子，我在这里是
the use of the Random class and I'm going to create
使用Random类，我将创建
an infinite stream of random integers and then
无限的随机整数流，然后
what I want to do is I want to terminate that stream once
我想做的是一次终止该视频流
I've found a number which is greater than 256.
我发现一个大于256的数字。
In this case I simply say findFirst and I use
在这种情况下，我只是说findFirst而我使用
Lambda expression to say if i is greater than 256
Lambda表达式，表示我是否大于256
that will return true and that will then terminate
将返回true，然后将终止
the stream and r will be set to whatever that value
流和r将设置为该值
of the random number is, but we know it will be greater than
的随机数是，但我们知道它将大于
256. Now there are also situations
256.现在也有情况
where you use infinite stream, but you actually need
在这里使用无限流，但实际上需要
it to be infinite, so you don't want to terminate that stream, you want to continue
它是无限的，所以您不想终止该流，而是想要继续
using it for as long as the application runs.
在应用程序运行期间一直使用它。
What do we use as a terminal operation in that case?
在这种情况下，我们将什么用作终端操作？
You would think that a terminal operation means that you're actually
您会认为终端操作意味着您实际上是
terminating the stream,
终止流，
so it would stop, but we don't want to do that. In this case
因此它会停止，但我们不想这样做。在这种情况下
we can use the forEach method and this is a good example of where the
我们可以使用forEach方法，这是一个很好的例子
forEach method is actually applicable. We're going to talk about that later in this lesson.
forEach方法实际上是适用的。我们将在本课程的稍后部分讨论。
Here, the forEach method consumes
在这里，forEach方法消耗
each element on the input stream, but it doesn't
输入流上的每个元素，但不是
terminate it, so it's important that we can consume
终止它，所以我们可以消耗它很重要
the element from the stream, but we don't actually terminate it.
流中的元素，但实际上并没有终止它。
If we look at an example of that, what I've got here is some code I wrote for a
如果我们看一个例子，我在这里得到的是我为
particular project
特定项目
where i had a temperature sensor and the temperature sensor provided the
我有一个温度传感器，而温度传感器提供了
values of the temperature as a set of strings.
一组字符串的温度值。
I just did it infinitely, so long as it was running
只要它正在运行，我就可以无限做
you getting lines of text, which gave you the information about
您会收到几行文字，这为您提供了有关
the temperature from sensor.
传感器的温度。
What I wanted to do with this was to take the reading, which was in Fahrenheit,
我想做的就是阅读华氏度的读数，
and convert it to Celsius. One of the other things is that the
并将其转换为摄氏温度另一件事是
text that was being returned always had a capital F at the end
返回的文本末尾总是大写F
to indicate it was Fahrenheit. I also wanted
表示是华氏温度。我也想
to notify listener, if there was one present, of changes
通知侦听器（如果存在）的更改
if the temperature changed. This is the code that I had.
如果温度变化。这是我的代码。
I had my thermalReader, which is a BufferedReader and I used the lines method
我有我的ThermalReader，它是BufferedReader，我使用了lines方法
to extract lines a text as a stream,
提取一行文本作为流，
passed that mapToDouble, which then just uses the
传递了mapToDouble，然后仅使用
parseDouble and removing the F from the end of the string,
parseDouble并从字符串末尾删除F，
so we can convert the temperature into a double value. Pass that into map,
因此我们可以将温度转换为双精度值。将其传递到地图中
which converts it from Fahrenheit into Celsius.
将其从华氏温度转换为摄氏温度。
Pass that into filter, so that we can test whether the
将其传递给过滤器，以便我们可以测试是否
current temperature is different to the new temperature.
当前温度与新温度不同。
Then use peek to
然后用窥视
take any values that are different
取任何不同的值
and look to see if we have a listener. So I use an Optional for the listener;
看看我们是否有一个听众。因此，我对侦听器使用了Optional；
if it's present then we update the listener by calling the temperatureChanged
如果存在，那么我们通过调用temperatureChanged来更新侦听器
method
方法
passing in the new temperature. To terminate the stream
传递新的温度。终止流
we use forEach and, in this case, what forEach is going to do
我们使用forEach，在这种情况下，forEach将要做什么
is consume the temperature and it's going to set the
是消耗温度，这将设置
current temperature to be whatever the new value is.
当前温度为新值。
To summarize this section,
总结本节，
we can see that we can have streams which are both finite
我们可以看到我们可以同时拥有有限的流
and infinite and how we use that depends on
和无限以及我们如何使用它取决于
how we actually want to use. Unlike with imperative programming in Java, as we know
我们实际如何使用。众所周知，与Java中的命令式编程不同
it,
它，
we don't have the concept breaking out of a stream. But you can terminate a
我们没有一个源源不断的概念。但您可以终止
stream,
流，
using findFirst or findAny based on a
使用findFirst或findAny基于
condition being true at a certain point. So we can have that
条件在某一点上为真。所以我们可以拥有
idea of processing until we get to the point where that
处理的想法，直到我们到达那个点
thing is true.
事情是真的。
If we want to use an infinite stream then we can use infinitely.
如果我们要使用无限流，则可以无限使用。
We can use that forEach method to consume the
我们可以使用forEach方法来消耗
elements to the stream, but without actually terminating
流中的元素，但没有实际终止
the stream that's being generated. That
正在生成的流。那
is the end of this part of the lesson.
是本节课程的结尾。